The Agecroft Collection
The Agecroft Collection
- Documents relating to members of the Buck Family, 1782-1895; 1 sub-series, 129 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/11
  - Articles of Agreement between Benjamin Vinter and John Hull, Jun 1807; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 14; GB/418/Agecroft/11/36
  - Transfer certificates for Manchester, Sheffield and Lincolnshire Railway [?belonging to] Elizabeth Hull, 1853; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 15; GB/418/Agecroft/11/37
  - Loan interest statement [for the] North Union Railway [?belonging to] Elizabeth Hull, 30 Jun 1861; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 16; GB/418/Agecroft/11/38
  - Letters concerning the Manchester, Sheffield and Lincolnshire Railway, 31 Aug 1858; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 17; GB/418/Agecroft/11/39
  - Indenture of lease between John Dauntesey and John Catterall for lands at Agecroft, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 18; GB/418/Agecroft/11/40
  - Lease [concerning?], nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 19; GB/418/Agecroft/11/41
    From Rev John Dauntesey to Mr Michael Norten.
  - Account of Messrs Edward Heath and sons in account with Mr Dauntesey Foxton, 31 May 1875; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 20; GB/418/Agecroft/11/42
  - Statement of rent account with J S Butler, Poulton-le-Fylde, 14 May 1869; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 21; GB/418/Agecroft/11/43
    The Trustees of the late John Dauntesey esq
  - Proposals made by John Dauntesey to James Westbrook Price concerning the lands he holds under the said John Dauntesey, 8 Aug 1801; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 22; GB/418/Agecroft/11/44
  - Letter to Mr Forshaw, solicitor, from Charles Molloy, 23 May 1818; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 23; GB/418/Agecroft/11/45
  - Agreement of co-partnership between Mr Benjamin Newton and W Hale, Jun 1807; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 24; GB/418/Agecroft/11/46
  - Bond for performance of Covenants in a lease, 17 Dec 1782; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 25; GB/418/Agecroft/11/47
    From Ralph Gregory and John Cookson to Rev Mr Dauntesey
  - Letter to Dr R Buck from Charles Molloy, 10 Aug 1818; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 26; GB/418/Agecroft/11/48
  - Accounts: the Revd Richard Buck and Miss Hull to Henry Gaskell, 9 Sep 1840; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 27; GB/418/Agecroft/11/49
  - An Act to enable the trustees of the will of Thomas Peter Legh to purchase estates for the benefit of their trust, 1811; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 28; GB/418/Agecroft/11/50
    [Royal Assent 15 Jun 1811] 51 Geo III Sess 1811
  - Notice to appoint arbitrator, 17 Sep 1868; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 29; GB/418/Agecroft/11/51
    From Messrs Knowles to Mrs Catherine Dauntesey Foxton
  - Release [of?], 30 Oct 1848; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 30; GB/418/Agecroft/11/52
    From Mr William Ride and others to Messrs Buck and Pountain
  - Schedule of papers relating to Mr John Watson's cottage in Thistleton, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 31; GB/418/Agecroft/11/53
  - Account: Robert Dauntesey esq to Robinson and Son, 1876; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 32; GB/418/Agecroft/11/54
  - Notice by Mrs Foxton appointing Mr Elias Dorning as her arbitrator, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 33; GB/418/Agecroft/11/55
    From Mrs C Dauntesey Foxton to Messrs Knowles.
  - Order confirming Dr Bucks purchase absolutely: Crosse v Ormerod, 23 Apr 1816; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 34; GB/418/Agecroft/11/56
  - Order for payments of debts and mortgages to be executed: Crosse v Ormerod, 10 Dec 1803; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 35; GB/418/Agecroft/11/57
  - Mr William Hankinson's agreement, 12 Dec 1821; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 36; GB/418/Agecroft/11/58
    With copy lease from Richard Buck and Elizabeth Hull to William Hankinson, for land in Pendlebury
  - Document referring to rental of land in the Manor of Ambleside from Lord Lonsdale to John Brenchley, 21 Feb 1842; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 37; GB/418/Agecroft/11/59
  - Petition re Robert Buck's purchase of land from Richard Crosse [now Richard Legh], George Heron et al, 14 Mar 1816; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 38; GB/418/Agecroft/11/60
  - Copy of a general report concerning Crosse and Ormerod, 21 Dec 1801; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 39; GB/418/Agecroft/11/61
  - Notice of intended application to Parliament, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 40; GB/418/Agecroft/11/62
    East Lancashire Railway (Bill no 1) Robert Buck and Elizabeth Hull. No 1. Township of Pendlebury. Parish of Eccles.
  - Notice of intended application to Parliament, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 41; GB/418/Agecroft/11/63
    East Lancashire Railway (Bill no 1) Robert Buck and Elizabeth Hull. No 1 Township of Broughton, Parish of Manchester.
  - Notice of intended application to Parliament, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 42; GB/418/Agecroft/11/64
    East Lancashire Railway (Bill no 10) Robert Buck and Elizabeth Hull. No 1 Township of Clifton, Parish of Eccles.
  - Notice of intended application to Parliament, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 43; GB/418/Agecroft/11/65
    East Lancashire Railway (Bill no 2) Robert Buck and Elizabeth Hull. No 2 Township of Prestwich otherwise Prestwich cum Oldham, Parish of Prestwich cum Oldham.
  - Notice of intended application to Parliament, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 44; GB/418/Agecroft/11/66
  - Probate of Miss M Buck, 27 Mar 1855; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 45; GB/418/Agecroft/11/67
  - Deed of Covenant between John Buck and Robert Buck, 6 Nov 1856; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 46; GB/418/Agecroft/11/68
  - Counterpart of lease of printworks and closes of land at Agecroft within Pendlebury, co Lancs, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 47; GB/418/Agecroft/11/69
    Term: 14 years.
  - Declaration of trust by Miss Hull and Robert and John Buck esqs, 25 Apr 1844; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 48; GB/418/Agecroft/11/70
    Of a sum of 10,000 settled on Rev Joseph Foxton and his wife and their issue and advances on mortgage of freehold estates in the County of Lancaster
  - Copy settlement made previous to the marriage of Mr Fredk and Josh Foxton with Miss Catherine Dauntesey Buck, 28 Jun 1834; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 49; GB/418/Agecroft/11/71
  - Draft demise of a cottage and premises in Thistleton to secure £95 16s 11d and interest, 1827; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 50; GB/418/Agecroft/11/72
    From Mr John Watson Senr and Mr John Watson Junr to Robert Buck esq
  - Abstract of lease of an estate in Much Hoole, co Lancs, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 51; GB/418/Agecroft/11/73
    From Peter Legh esq to Mr Richard Hunt for three lives.
  - Copy agreement for 'Liswainey', Torquay, 9 Apr 1892; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 52; GB/418/Agecroft/11/74
    From Mrs CTA Hatter to Robert Dauntesey esq
  - Sale particulars of freehold estates, situate at Hoole, otherwise Much Hoole, Bretherton, and Eccleston, co Lancs, 1815; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 53; GB/418/Agecroft/11/75
    To be sold…at the Black Horse, in Hoole, on Thursday 21 Sep 1815. Crosse v Ormerod.
  - Account of Foreign and Colonial Government Stocks [?of John Hull esq, decd], nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 54; GB/418/Agecroft/11/76
  - Loan Interest Statements, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 55; GB/418/Agecroft/11/77
  - Blue envelope addressed to Edward Heath esq containing 'A Catalogue of Watches Jewels etc to be kept in Agecroft Hall as Heirlooms', 1878; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 56; GB/418/Agecroft/11/78
    Also coat of arms
  - Copy of Martin's report: Crosse and Ormerod, 13 Feb 1816; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 57; GB/418/Agecroft/11/79
  - Notice to Robert Buck re payment of purchase money, 28 Oct 1816; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 58; GB/418/Agecroft/11/80
    Richard Crosse and George Heron v Martha Ann Ormerod, Elizabeth Charlotte Legh et al
  - Declaration of Trust as to the sum of £1150 lent to Mr Saul Wainwright out of Mrs Foxton's separate trust estate, 30 Mar 1870; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 59; GB/418/Agecroft/11/81
  - An agreement between Robert Neill and sons of Strangeways and Robert Dauntesey of Agecroft Hall, [1894]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 60; GB/418/Agecroft/11/82
  - Measurement and rent due on coal, 25 Jun 1889; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 61; GB/418/Agecroft/11/83
    Also accompanying letter to Robert Dauntesey from Elias Dorning and sons, 24 Jun 1889
  - Surrender and conveyance of Agecroft Hall Estate, 29 May 1841; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 16; GB/418/Agecroft/11/84
    From Rev Richard Buck to Robert and John Buck esqs
  - Lease for a year [?of Agecroft Hall Estate], 26 Jun 1834; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 17; GB/418/Agecroft/11/85
    From Rev Richard Buck and Miss Buck to Miss Hull
  - Release of Agecroft Hall Estate, 27 Jun 1834; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 18; GB/418/Agecroft/11/86
  - Release of Agecroft Hall Estate, 15 May 1841; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 19; GB/418/Agecroft/11/87
    From Rev Richard Buck and Miss Margaret Buck to Miss Hull
  - Mutual release of claims by Rev Richard Buck and Robert Buck et al, 18 May 1841; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 20; GB/418/Agecroft/11/88
  - Release in fee of Agecroft Hall Estate, 28 Oct 1843; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 21; GB/418/Agecroft/11/89
    From John Buck esq to Miss Hull
  - Notes (on parchment) relating to the family of Dauntesey in Wiltshire, signed by Jo Philipott, Somerset Herald, 19th century; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 1; GB/418/Agecroft/11/90
  - Evidence certificates and declarations as to title to Agecroft Estate, 1800-[?]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 2; GB/418/Agecroft/11/91
  - Account: Dr Buck to Edward Forshaw, 1816; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 3; GB/418/Agecroft/11/92
  - Abstract of the title of Thomas Legh esq and his Trustees to estates in Hoole, Bretherton, Eccleston and Ulness Walton, co Lancs, [Early 19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 4; GB/418/Agecroft/11/93
    Sold under a Decree in Chancery in the cause 'Crosse and Ormerod'. Lots 14 and 15
  - Copy of Mr Booth's opinion on Dr Buck's purchase [by Mr Forshaw, Solicitor, Preston], 3 Aug 1818; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 5; GB/418/Agecroft/11/94
  - Counterpart lease of the Agecroft Print Works, 13 Oct 1823; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 6; GB/418/Agecroft/11/95
    The Revd Richard Buck and his wife and Mill Hull to Messrs Taylor Worlidge and Co
  - Draft Lease of the Agecroft Print Works, 14 Feb 1828; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 7; GB/418/Agecroft/11/96
    From Rev Richard and Mrs Buck and Miss Elizabeth Hull to Mr William Bayley
  - Agreement, 30 Oct 1833; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 8; GB/418/Agecroft/11/97
    Between the Company of Proprietors of the Manchester, Bolton and Bury Canal Navigation Railway and Miss Hull and Rev Richard Buck and others.
  - Counterpart lease of the Bin Mine, Crombroke Mine and Rams Mine, Agecroft Hall, 31 Oct 1843; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 9; GB/418/Agecroft/11/98
    From Miss Elizabeth Hull and Mr Robert Buck to Messrs Robert, Thomas, John and James Knowles.
  - Duplicate lease of the Agecroft Print Works land etc situate in Pendlebury in Eccles, co Lancs, 12 June 1851; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 10; GB/418/Agecroft/11/99
    From Miss Elizabeth Hull and Robert Buck to the executors of the late Mr William Bayley.
  - Inventory as directed by the last will and testament of Miss Margaret Buck, decd, 1855; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 11; GB/418/Agecroft/11/100
  - Receipts and Payments between Elias Dorning in account with John Dauntesey esq, concerning Agecroft Hall Estate, Jun 1865-Jul 1867; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 12; GB/418/Agecroft/11/101
  - Plan of the site of Agecroft Print Works, 18 Jan 1869; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 13; GB/418/Agecroft/11/102
  - Counterpart lease of farm lands and buildings situate on Agecroft Estate in Pendlebury, 9 Jul 1869; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 14; GB/418/Agecroft/11/103
    From Mrs Catherine D Foxton to Mr T Westbrook
    Term: 14 years
  - Agreement for putting water pipes under a portion of the Agecroft Hall Estate, 24 Sep 1869; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 15; GB/418/Agecroft/11/104
    From Mrs C Dauntesey Foxton to Frederick Craven esq
  - Declaration of Trust as to the sum of £4,000 invested with the Great Western Railway Company, 20 Feb 1869; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 16; GB/418/Agecroft/11/105
    Mr Edward Heath as trustee for Mrs Foxton and others
  - Codicil of the will of Mrs Catherine Dauntesey Foxton, of Agecroft Hall, 17 May 1872; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 17; GB/418/Agecroft/11/106
  - Residuary account re Margaret Buck, decd, 16 Feb 1875; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 18; GB/418/Agecroft/11/107
  - Copy draft conveyance of life interest in certain freehold property in the parish of St Harmon in the county of Radnor, 1876; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 19; GB/418/Agecroft/11/108
    From Mrs CD Foxton to Rev GFH Foxton
  - Agreement for lease of plot of land, part of Agecroft Estate, 27 Nov 1876; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 20; GB/418/Agecroft/11/109
    From Mrs Catherine Dauntesey Foxton to the Mayor, Aldermen and Burgesses of the borough of Salford
  - Loose scraps of letters, bills etc mainly Robert Buck and Robert Dauntesey, c 1840 & c 1883; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 21; GB/418/Agecroft/11/110
  - Plan of part of the Agecroft Hall Estate belonging to Robert Dauntesey esq, 31 Oct 1885; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 22; GB/418/Agecroft/11/111
  - Agreement as to lights overlooking land at Agecroft, Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 7 no 23; GB/418/Agecroft/11/112
    Robert Dauntesey esq with the Lancashire and Yorkshire Railway co
  - Certificate of Contract for redemption of Land Tax for Robert Richard Buck, 23 May 1799; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 173; GB/418/Agecroft/11/113
  - Demise of a cottage, public house and premises in Thistleton and Staining to secure £95 16s 11d interest, 2 Feb 1827; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 174; GB/418/Agecroft/11/114
    From John Watson to Robert Buck
  - Wills and codicils, 1811-1878; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a
    - Wills and codicils, 1811-1878; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1
      - Office copy of the will of Rev John Dauntesey, 10 Oct 1811; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 1; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/1
      - Attested copies of the will and codicils of Rev Richard Buck, 18 Sep 1839; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 2; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/2
      - Attested copies of the will and codicils of Rev Richard Buck, 1839; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 3; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/3
      - Copy will and codicils of the Revd Richard Buck, decd, 18 Sep 1839; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 4; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/4
      - Copy will and codicils of Rev Richard Buck, 18 Sep 1839; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 5; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/5
      - Duplicate will of Robert Buck, 11 Jan 1854; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 6; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/6
      - Duplicate will of Miss Eliz Hull, 11 Jan 1854; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 7; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/7
      - Attested copy of the will of Miss Margaret Buck, reference to legacy and succession duty, 17 Oct 1854; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 8; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/8
      - Attested copy of the will of Miss Margaret Buck, 1854; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 9; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/9
      - Will of John Dauntesey esq, 27 Jun 1867; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 10; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/10
      - Will of Rev FJ Foxton, 3 Sep 1868; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 11; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/11
      - Office copy of the will of Rev Frederick Joseph Foxton, 3 Sep 1868; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 12; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/12
      - Probate of the will of Rev FJ Foxton, 29 Apr 1871; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 13; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/13
        Will dated 3 Sep 1868
      - Sixth codicil to Mrs CD Foxton's will (duplicate), 187[?]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 14; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/14
      - Duplicate codicil to Mrs C Dauntesey Foxton's will, 19 Feb 1878; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 6 no 15; GB/418/Agecroft/11/a/1/15
- Documents relating to members of the Chisenhall Family, 1572-1738; 7 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/12
  These documents relate largely to lands in Gorthwaite and Ulverston, sold to various parties in 1606.
  - Conveyance of messuages, lands etc in Rossett, Goldorswith, Shorediks in Ulverston in Fournes co Lancs, 6 Mar 1572; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 360; GB/418/Agecroft/12/1
    From Christopher Anderton of Lostock co Lancs, esq to Richard Chisnall of Gray's Inn co Middlesex, esq and his heirs for ever
  - Grant of deeds concerning several messuages, 26 Mar 1605; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 361; GB/418/Agecroft/12/2
    From Edward Chisnall co Lancs, esq to Allan Coward of Gorthwait co Lancs, yeo, William Coward, Henry Coward, Thomas Coward of Gorthwait aforesaid, husbandmen, and others
    4 Jas
  - Conveyance of messuages etc in Gorthwaite and Ulverston co Lancs, 26 Mar 1605; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 362; GB/418/Agecroft/12/3
    From Edward Chisnall of Chisnall co Lancs, esq to Allan Coward of Gorthwaite in Fournes co Lancs, yeo, and his heirs for ever
  - Acknowledgement of the receipt of certain evidences concerning lands in Rossett, Gorthwaite and [?Shoredickes] in the parish of Ulverston in Fournes co Lancs, 29 Sep 1606; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 363; GB/418/Agecroft/12/4
    From Allan Cowarde of Gorthwaite co Lancs, yeo, and others, to Edward Chisnall of Chisnall co Lancs, esq
  - Assignment of the manors of Chisenhale, Wrightington, Shevington, Coppall, Rivington alias Revington, Laughtree, Holland, Hourerly and Lancaster co Lancs, nd [?17th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 364; GB/418/Agecroft/12/5
    From William Chisenhale, son and heir apparent of Sir Edward Chisenhale of Chisenhale Hall co Lancs, kt to Robert Williamson of Lincoln's Inn co Midd, gent, to secure £1200 and interest.
  - A case for Counsel's opinion relating to the Chisenhall Family, 1738; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 365; GB/418/Agecroft/12/6
  - Deed to lead the uses of a fine of the Manor or Lordship of Pirliston alias Prilleston, alias Billingford, co Norfolk, 1693; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 370; GB/418/Agecroft/12/7
    Between Sir Edward Chisenhale of Chisenhale, co Lancs and William Chisenhale esq, his son and heir apparent by Dame Elizabeth his late lady, dec, late called Elizabeth Playters, and Robert Camell of Disse, co Norfolk, gent and others (Trustees)
- Miscellaneous Documents, 1630-1834; 17 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/13
  - Lease of a messuage etc in James Street, Covent Garden, in the parish of St Martin in the Fields, co Midd, 2 Jul 1638; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 368; GB/418/Agecroft/13/1
    From Sir William Clayton of Satterlye, co Suffolk, knt and bart to Edward Maylard of the parish of St Martin in the Fields aforesaid
    Term: 7 years
  - Declaration of allegiance to King Charles II by William White of Bashall, co Yorks, esq, 8 Jun 1660; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 369; GB/418/Agecroft/13/2
  - Copy of a Pedigree Roll of the Family of Dansey, in Brinsop co Hereford, coming down to the year 1628, 19 Jul 1783; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 260; GB/418/Agecroft/13/3
  - Note as to the arms of Dauntesey of Brinsop from the Heralds College, London, 16 Jan 1777; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 261; GB/418/Agecroft/13/4
  - Rough schedule and list of the deeds relating to the Agecroft Estate etc, c 1630; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 263; GB/418/Agecroft/13/5
  - Schedule of deeds delivered to Mr Henry Gaskell and bill from Henry Gaskell to Miss Hull, 9 Nov 1833 & 1834; 2 items; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 Unnumbered; GB/418/Agecroft/13/6
  - Receipt for a pair of spurs and leathers, 17 Jan 1824; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 268; GB/418/Agecroft/13/7
  - An abstract of Mr Dauntesey's deeds relating to the title of his Estate in Pendlebury etc, 1721-1759; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 269; GB/418/Agecroft/13/8
  - Receipts and disbursements on Mr Dauntesey's account, 1724; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 270; GB/418/Agecroft/13/9
  - Rental of the Agecroft Estate, 1724-1730; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 271; GB/418/Agecroft/13/10
  - Mr Starkie's accounts in levying the fine, Feb 1757; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 272; GB/418/Agecroft/13/11
  - Rough plan of lands in Pendlebury belonging to the Rev Mr Dauntesey and to Carrington Chapel, nd [?18th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 273; GB/418/Agecroft/13/12
  - An estimate of the taxes, measure, and valuation of the demesne lands at Agecroft, the property of the Rev Mr John Dauntesey, by Hugh Oldham, 1778-1780; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 unnumbered; GB/418/Agecroft/13/13
    1778, 1779 & 1780
    Linen backed paper
  - Plan of the demesne lands of Agecroft in the parishes of Eccles and Prestwich, 1778 & 1779; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 274; GB/418/Agecroft/13/14
  - An Act to enable Rev Richard Buck, clerk, and Margaret his wife, and the survivor of them, to grant leases of a moiety of coal mines, 1823; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 275; GB/418/Agecroft/13/15
    Within the estates devised by the will of John Hull, decd, in the county of Lancaster [Royal Assent, 17 Jun 1823] 4 George IV Sess 1823.
  - Miscellaneous letters and memoranda, [?18th century-?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 276; GB/418/Agecroft/13/16
  - Bill from Henry Gaskell to Miss Hull, Chorley, 1832-1834; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 4 no 277; GB/418/Agecroft/13/17
  - Copy of Mrs Martha Peckard's will, 24 Feb 1801; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 371; GB/418/Agecroft/13/18
    Mrs Martha Peckard of Fletton co Hunts was the widow of Rev Peter Peckard DD, Dean of Peterborough and Master of the College of St Mary Magdalene, Cambridge. Rev Richard Buck, rector of Fletton, Fellow of Magdalene College, was one of the executors of her will.